So the answer is no, that even with any
答案是 “No” 即使有这些限制中的
of these restrictions, we still don't have a good
任一限制 依然不能很好地做出定义
definition. So, let's consider all the restrictions. So, the
我们来看看所有限制条件
first one was, if everyone is friends with Alice. So
第一个是 如果所有人都和 Alice 是好友
that would only work if they don't have any
只有当他们都没有任何其他好友时 才能成立
other friends. Let's say this is Alice. We've got
假设这是 Alice
Bob and Charlie. They're both friends with Alice. But
这是 Bob 和 Charlie 他们都是 Alice 的好友
Bob is also friends with Charlie and Charlie is friends
但是 Bob 也是 Charlie 的好友
with Bob. That means that to figure out the popularity of
Charlie 是 Bob 的好友 这表明 要算出 Bob 的受欢迎程度
Bob we need to know the popularity of Charlie. To figure
我们需要知道 Charlie 的受欢迎程度
out the popularity of Charlie we need to know the popularity
要算出 Charlie 的受欢迎程度
of Alice as well as the popularity of Bob. So we're never
我们需要知道 Alice 和 Bob 的受欢迎程度
going to get to a solution. We are going to keep
我们始终也得不到结果
bouncing back and forth between Bob and Charlie doing this. The
我们将在 Bob 和 Charlie 之间不断循环
second choice only if no one is friends with Alice. Well,
第二个选项是仅当任何人都不是 Alice 的好友
if no one was friends with Alice, that would remove these links.
如果任何人都不是 Alice 的好友 则需要删掉这两个箭头
It doesn't solve our problem. We're still not going to be able
并不能解决我们的问题
to give a popularity score for Bob and Charlie. The third choice
我们依然无法算出 Bob 和 Charlie 的受欢迎程度
only if there is a friendship path from everyone in the graph
第三个选项是仅当图中有一个好友路径
that eventually reaches Alice. So adding this link would provide that property,
最终会抵达 Alice 添加这个箭头即可满足这一特性
but it still doesn't solve our problem. It doesn't give us a
但是依然无法解答我们的问题
way to figure out the popularity of Charlie, because to know that,
我们无法算出 Charlie 的受欢迎程度
we need to know the popularity of Bob, which we need to
因为我们需要知道 Bob 的受欢迎程度
know the popularity of Charlie for. We still end up in this cycle.
这样的话 我们就需要知道 Charlie 的受欢迎程度 又进入这一死循环了
The final choice seems, possibly more promising. It says
最后一个选项似乎正确
there are no cycles in the graph, so if
条件是图中没有循环
we want to remove this cycle. We could do
我们可以删掉这个箭头 这样就没循环了
this. In this case, we'd be okay, right? We could
这样的话 是不是就满足条件了？
figure out the popularity of Bob, by figuring out
我们可以通过算出 Charlie 的受欢迎程度
the popularity of Charlie, which depends on the popularity
来算出 Bob 的受欢迎程度 Charlie 的受欢迎程度取决于
of Alice. Where we're not okay, is if Bob
Alice 的受欢迎程度 但是如果 Bob 还有其他好友
has another friend. Let's say Bob is friends with Diana.
假设 Bob 是 Diana 的好友
Well then, to figure out the popularity of Diana,
那么要算出 Diana 的受欢迎程度
we need to know the popularity of Bob. Where
我们需要知道 Bob 的受欢迎程度
it breaks down is, suppose we also have Diana
存在问题的情况是 假设还有 Diana 和 Edgar
and Edgar, and Diana's friends with Edgar. To figure out
Diana 是 Edgar 的好友
the popularity score of Diana, we need to know the popularity score
要算出 Diana 的受欢迎程度 我们需要知道 Edgar 的受欢迎程度
of Edgar. We don't have a cycle, but we don't have an answer
虽然没有死循环 但是也没有答案
either. To figure out the popularity of Edgar,. We are going to go through
要算出 Edgar 的受欢迎程度 我们需要看看
Edgar's friends, and the way the Python code is written. This could actually
Edgar 的好友 对于 Python 代码来说 实际上有可能可行
work, right? Because if we define popularity when you have no friends.
对吧？因为如果我们定义没有好友时的受欢迎程度
Well, if the friends of p is empty, when we go through this
如果 friends(p) 为空 当我们遍历这一循环时
loop, the score is going to be 0. So, if you answered there are
score 将为 0 所以如果答案是没有循环
no cycles. That's at least worth credit for this, that could be correct.
至少这种情况可能正确
In terms of the mathematical definition, it doesn't make very good
但是对于数学定义来说 则不够严谨
sense. We still needed a way to know the popularity of
我们依然需要知道 Edgar 的受欢迎程度
Edgar. We've sort of defined things in this case to say,
这种情况的定义就相当于
if you have no friends, your popularity score is zero. And
如果没有好友 那么受欢迎程度的得分将是 0
the Python code will work for that. But it's not a
Python 代码可以表示这种情况
good way to define popularity. So its very arbitrary to say
但是这并不能很好地定义受欢迎程度
we're going to make Alice the one whose popularity score is predefined
我们不能专断地说 假设 Alice 的受欢迎程度得分是 1
as one. There is nothing Alice could do to make herself
Alice 根本没法提高她自己的受欢迎程度
more popular. That's not very fair to
这样对 Alice 来说不太公平
Alice and it doesn't give us meaningful scores.
也无法提供有意义的得分